let Flamingo = [
    {
        "question": "What had been put up on the bulletin-board?",
        "answer": "The French districts of Alsace and Lorraine had been taken over by the Prussians. Hence, the bulletin board displayed the news that an order had come from Berlin to teach only German in the schools of Alsace and Lorraine."
    },
    {
        "question": "The people in this story suddenly realise how precious their language is to them. What shows you this? Why does this happen?",
        "answer": "He asked his fellow Frenchmen to protect their language as it is like a key to the prison they were about to be in. This made the people realize how precious their language was to them. This also shows the people's love for their country and culture which is reflected through their love for the French language."
    },
    {
        "question": "What was Franz expected to be prepared with for school that day?",
        "answer": " Franz was expected to be prepared with the use of 'Participles' that day. His teacher M. Hamel had said that he would question the children on participles"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is Saheb happy working at the tea-stall? Explain.",
        "answer": "No, Saheb is not happy working at the tea-stall. He is no longer his own master. His face has lost the carefree look. The steel canister seems heavier than the plastic bag he would carry with ease earlier."
    },
    {
        "question": "What makes the city of Firozabad famous?",
        "answer": "The city of Firozabad is famous for its bangles. Every other family in Firozabad is engaged in making bangles. It is the centre of India's glass-blowing industry. Families have spent generations working around furnaces, welding glass, making bangles for the women in the land."
    },
    {
        "question": "Mention the hazards of working in the glass bangles industry.",
        "answer": "Glass blowing, welding and soldering pieces of glass are all health hazards. Even the dust from polishing the glass of bangles adversely affects the eyes and even adults go blind. Thus, the surroundings, prevailing conditions and the type of job involved-all prove risky to the health of the workers"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the “misadventure ” that William Douglas speaks about?  ",
        "answer": "The “misadventure” that William Douglas speaks about is the one where he was thrown into a swimming pool by an older boy. He found it difficult to breathe and almost drowned. He made three unsuccessful attempts to jump out of the water. He would have drowned if someone hadn't brought him out of the water."
    },
    {
        "question": "How did Douglas overcome his fear of water? ",
        "answer": " Douglas' journey of truly overcoming his fear to its tiniest vestiges began. He swam alone in the pool. He went to Lake Wentworth to dive. He tried every possible stroke he learnt. Finally, in his diving expedition, in the Warm Lake, he conquered his fear completely."
    },
    {
        "question": "What made the peddler think that he had indeed fallen into a rattrap?",
        "answer": "The peddler considered the whole world as a big rattrap, its sole purpose being to set baits for people. The joys and riches of this world are nothing but tempting baits and anyone who is tempted by them was captured by the rattrap which completely closed in on him."
    },

    {
        "question": " Why was Edla happy to see the gift left by the peddler?  ",
        "answer": "Edla showed great trust in him by letting him stay at their manor on the Christmas Eve. But the news about the robbery had left her dejected. So she was overjoyed when she reached home to find the package and the letter left by the peddler. This gesture of appreciation from the peddler made her happy."
    },
    {
        "question": "Draw the character sketch of the peddler ? [The Rattrap]  ",
        "answer": "Instead of flowing some goodness in him, he had the human weakness of petty thievery and begging to keep his body and soul together. He wore rags and hunger gleamed in his eyes. He went round selling self-made small rattrape of wire. Devoid of any sheltering place, he could spend his night wherever he desired. Mostly he came across sour faces and was a victim of his cruel circumstances. He could of knock at the door any person for his night shelter. "
    },
    {
        "question": "Why did Gandhi agree to a settlement of 25 per cent refund to the farmers? ",
        "answer": "He wanted the poor farmers to realise that they too had rights and that they need not really live in fear of the British landlords. Therefore, although he had initially quoted a 50 percent refund, he later agreed to a settlement of 25 percent refund to the farmers. Besides, Gandhi was interested in long-term solutions rather than immediate benefits"
    },
    {
        "question": "How was Gandhi able to influence lawyers? Give instances? ",
        "answer": "Gandhi asked the lawyers what they would do if he was sentenced to prison. They said that they had come to advise him. If he went to jail, they would go home. Then Gandhi asked them about the injustice to the sharecroppers. The lawyers held consultations. They came to the conclusion that it would be shameful desertion if they went home. So, they told Gandhi that they were ready to follow him into jail."
    },
    {
        "question": "What work did the 'office boy' do in the Gemini Studios, Why did he join the studios? Why was he disappointed?",
        "answer": "The office boy used to apply makeup on the actors who were part of the crowd in a film. He would mix paint in a large vessel and apply, rather literally slap them on their faces. He was a poet too. He joined the studios with a dream to become a star or a screenwriter or a lyrics writer. He was disappointed because he couldn’t achieve any of it and stayed in the same position as an office boy."
    },
    {
        "question": "]Did the people at Gemini Studios have any particular political affiliations?  ",
        "answer": "Most people at Gemini Studios were followers of Gandhiji. They didn’t have other political affiliations. However, there were strong opposers of communism."
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the Boss of Gemini Studios?",
        "answer": "Poets And Pancakes. Who was The Boss of Gemini Studios? The Boss of the Gemini Studios was Mr. S.S."
    },

    {
        "question": "Why was Kothamangalam Subbu considered No. 2 in Gemini Studios? ",
        "answer": " Kothamangalam Subbu succeeded in securing the place closest to The Boss by means of flattery. He was not brilliant but a rather cheerful person and exceedingly loyal to The Boss. He offered solutions whenever The Boss was in a fix. Thus, the other employees considered him No."
    },
    {
        "question": "Why do most celebrity writers despise being interviewed?  ",
        "answer": "Celebrity writers believe that interviews unduly interfere in their private lives. They regard themselves as victims of interviews. They claim that the interview in some way 'diminishes' them, just like some ancient cultures believed that a portrait of a person takes away his soul"
    },
    {
        "question": "Do you think Umberto Eco likes being interviewed? Give reasons for your opinion.",
        "answer": "Yes, Umberto Eco, in all possibilities, likes being interviewed. He readily answers every question asked by Mukund Padmanabhan in an energetic and lively manner. He does not seem apprehensive about sharing his secrets, experiences and opinions with the interviewer, and consequently, the world."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was it most likely that the two girls would find work after school?  ",
        "answer": " The two girls, Sophie and Jansie, were already destined for a job in the biscuit factory and it was likely that they would work there after school."
    },
    {
        "question": "Does Geoff believe what Sophie says about her meeting with Danny Casey?  ",
        "answer": "No, Geoff does not believe what Sophie says about her meeting. He calls it “the unlikeliest thing [he] ever heard”"
    },
    {
        "question": "How would you describe the character and temperament of Sophie’s father?",
        "answer": "Sophie's father has a plumpy face looking grimy and sweaty. He doesn't seem to be a soft or sophisticated man. Sophie fears his aggressive manliness. He is a realist and does not believe in his daughter's wild stories."
    }


]
let FlamingoPoetry = [
    {
        "question": "What is the kind of pain and ache that the poet feels? ",
        "answer": "The poetess feels pain on seeing the pale and corpse-like face of her mother and it's said that her old familiar pain or the ache returns. Perhaps she has experienced this fear since her childhood. She realizes that her mother's face has become like the withered moon of the winter season"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the poet want for the children of the slums? How can their lives be made to change?",
        "answer": "He believes that their life can be changed by providing them access to education and other resources. This would help them break out of the shackles of poverty. With the right amenities and resources, they can actually experience the world that they see in the pictures that decorate their classroom's walls"
    },
    {
        "question": "Do you think the poet advocates total inactivity and death?  ",
        "answer": "No, the poet does not advocate total inactivity and death. In fact, he says “What I want should not be confused with total inactivity”. He describes people walking peacefully, doing nothing. He wants us to introspect, which can happen only when one is alive and conscious."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the ‘sadness’ that the poet refers to in the poem? ",
        "answer": "The poet refers to the 'sadness' of failing to understand oneself in the monotonous existence of everyday life. He also finds it sad that humanity is moving towards its own ruins, owing to its unprecedented actions."
    },
    {
        "question": "List the things of beauty mentioned in the poem. ",
        "answer": "According to the poet, there are numerous things of beauty that help us forget our sorrows. These are the sun, the moon, old and young trees that provide shade to 'simple sheep', daffodils, clear streams of rivers, musk-roses in the forest and the lovely tales of mighty men"
    },
    {
        "question": "What makes human beings love life in spite of troubles and sufferings?  ",
        "answer": "Human beings love life in spite of troubles and sufferings because of the existence of several natural and beautiful things around them. These things of beauty never fade. They give joy and optimism to human mind, and thus, help in overcoming or bearing the troubles and sufferings"
    },
    {
        "question": "What image does the poet use to describe the beautiful bounty of the earth? ",
        "answer": "The poet uses the image of 'an endless fountain of immortal drink' to describe the beautiful bounty of the earth. The earth, like a fountain, pours unto us numerous beautiful sights like the sun, the moon, flowers, rivers and greenery"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the plea of the folk who had put up the roadside stand?",
        "answer": "The plea of the folk who had put up the roadside stand is to the passers by to stop over at their stand and buy their goods. They would have been content if even one car had stopped to inquire about the price of their goods."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the ‘childish longing’ that the poet refers to? Why is it ‘vain’? ",
        "answer": "The poet refers to the farmers' longing for customers at their roadside stall as “childish longing”. This is because no one stopped and even if they did, it was for asking direction or to buy gas. Hence, this child-like wait is 'vain'."
    },
    {
        "question": "Why do you think Aunt Jennifer’s hands are ‘fluttering through her wool’ in the second stanza? Why is she finding the needle so hard to pull? ",
        "answer": "Aunt Jenifer's hands are fluttering through her wool because she is frightened and subdued. Her marriage ring becomes a burden for her because it symbolizes how she is oppressed and controlled by her husband. This is why she is unable to even pull the needle."
    },
    {
        "question": "Do you sympathise with Aunt Jennifer? What is the attitude of the speaker towards Aunt Jennifer? ",
        "answer": "Yes the character of Aunt Jennifer wins our sympathy as a reader. Her ordeals and sufferings move the reader. Even the speaker in the poem shows sympathy and pity towards her. The speaker says that even after Aunt Jennifers death she will be terrified of her husband and the ordeals of her marriage."
    }
]

let Vistas = [
    {
        "question": "Reflecting on the story, what did you feel about Evans’ having the last laugh? ",
        "answer": "The Governor was happy that ultimately he was able to track him down using his intelligence and knowledge of German. However, Evans had planned a step ahead. With his successful escape, Evans definitely had a well earned last laugh."
    },
    {
        "question": "The two accounts that you have read above are based in two distant cultures. What is the commonality of theme found in both of them? ",
        "answer": "The autobiographical accounts included in the “Memories of Childhood” are by two women from socially marginalized sections in two distant cultures of the world. One highlights the evil practice of racial prejudice while the other talks about the hierarchical Indian caste system and untouchability. The first part traces how the author, a Native American, was victimized at the hands of the European staff of her boarding school. The second account gives a picture of the hardships and humiliations faced by the Indian ‘Dalits’ from the eyes of a third standard student. "
    },

    {
        "question": "Would Charley ever go back to the ticket counter on the third  ",
        "answer": "Answer: No, Charley will never go back to the third-level ticket-counter to purchase tickets for himself and his wife to Galesburg because his imagination was third-level."
    },
    {
        "question": "The modern world is full of insecurity, fear, war, worry and stress.’ What are the ways in which we attempt to overcome them?",
        "answer": "Simple activities like listening to music playing with pets an occasional dinner out watching cinema or plays or going to places like parks etc can go a long way in helping us get rid of stress boredom and insecurities."
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the Tiger King? Why does he get that name? ",
        "answer": "Jilani Jung Jung Bahadur, the king of Pratibandapuram, is known as the Tiger King. Ten days after his birth, a renowned astrologer prophesied that his “death comes from the Tiger.” After he became the king of Pratibandapuram and got to know of the prediction about his death, he went on a tiger killing spree."
    },
    {
        "question": "What will the Maharaja do to find the required number of tigers to kill?  ",
        "answer": "To get the required number of tigers to kill, the Maharaja asked his dewan to find a suitable girl for him to marry. A suitable girl for matrimonial alliance would be one who would not only come from a royal family but also belong to a state with a large tiger population."
    },
    {
        "question": "The world’s geological history is trapped in Antarctica.’ How is the study of this region useful to us? ",
        "answer": "The research of this Antarctic region gives us insight into the geological past of the planet. It gives an idea of how the world was before dividing into continents and nations. It shows how minor climate changes can change the shape of the region."
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is Antarctica the place to go to, to understand the earth’s present, past, and future? ",
        "answer": "The ice-sheets are breaking, and thus, global warming is setting in. Also, the beauty of the existing ice covered oceans is a source of inspiration to do whatever is possible to save and preserve its natural resources. Thus, Antarctica is definitely the place to go to understand the world"
    },
    {
        "question": "Will Dr Sadao be arrested on the charge of harbouring an enemy?  ",
        "answer": " Dr Sadao will be arrested on the charge of harbouring an enemy if somebody complains against him and discloses the secret. He, on humanitarian grounds as well as professional grounds, had tended a wounded war- prisoner which was officially a serious crime."
    },
    {
        "question": "What will Dr Sadao do to get rid of the man?  ",
        "answer": "He ultimately decided that he would let the prisoner escape as it wasn't safe for him to stay anymore. Dr. Sadao arranged a boat for him to row to the nearby unpopulated, ignored island. He also arranged a flashlight for coded signals, Japanese clothes, and food and stealthily bid him goodbye."
    },
    {
        "question": "Dr Sadao was compelled by his duty as a doctor to help the enemy soldier. What made Hana, his wife, sympathetic to him in the face of open defiance from the domestic staff?",
        "answer": "Dr. Sadao helped him due to his profession but Hana did helped him for supporting his husband and performing her duty towards her husband and for the humankind, so this duty towards her husband made her sympathetic towards the enemy."
    },
    {
        "question": "How does Jo want the story to end and why?  ",
        "answer": "Jo refused to accept the end where Roger Skunk's mother hits the wizard and that too without being hit back. She wanted the story to end with the wizard hitting back the mother skunk with his magic wand and chopping off her arms 'forcely'."
    },
    {
        "question": "Why does Jack insist that it was the wizard that was hit and not the mother? ",
        "answer": "jack insisted that it was the wizard that was hit and not the mother because he wanted to prove a point to Jo that the little Skunk loved his mother more than he loved all the other little animals and his mother knew what was right for him."
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is an adult’s perspective on life different from that of a child’s?",
        "answer": " An adult's perspective on life is different from that of a child because of the difference between their respective experiences and exposure to the world around them. An adult comes across all sorts of experiences—good or bad, pleasant or unpleasant, happy or sad, encouraging or discouraging."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is it that draws Derry towards Mr Lamb in spite of himself? ",
        "answer": "He has two arms, two legs, eyes ears, tongue and a brain. And if he has a firm mind, he can do better than others. It is by such words of encouragement that Mr. Lamb draws Derry to himself"
    },
    {
        "question": "Will Derry get back to his old seclusion or will Mr Lamb’s brief association effect a change in the kind of life he will lead in the future? ",
        "answer": " No, Derry will not get back to his seclusion. The brief association of Derry with Mr. Lamb boosted his self-confidence and helped him to respect his own self."
    },
    {
        "question": "What kind of a person was Evans? ",
        "answer": "Evans was a young and clever prisoner. He had escaped thrice from the prison for which he was known 'Evans the Break'. He had never involved himself in violence. He had quite a pleasant personality and was a star at the Christmas concert."
    }
]

let vImp = [
    {

        "question": " 51] Explain the given lines :   Trees sprinting, the merry children spillin  out of their homes, but after the airport’s  security check, standing a few yards away, I looked again at her, wan, pale as a late winter’s moon and felt that old familiar ache. ",

        "answer":`<a href="https://www.zigya.com/study/book?class=12&board=gbshse&subject=English&book=Flamingo&chapter=My+Mother+At+Sixty-Six&q_type=&q_topic=My+Mother+At+Sixty-Six+&q_category=E&question_id=ENEN12122286">ClickHere </a> For Answer`
    },
    {
        "question": " How in your opinion can Mukesh realise his dream ? ",
        "answer": "He can realise this dream with determination and hard work. There might be many obstacles on his way but a strong willpower will help him move towards the way to success. The fact that he is willing to walk a long distance in order to learn the vocation, underlines his firm resolve."
    },
    {
        "question": "Why did the peddler leave a Christmas gift for Edla ?  ",
        "answer": "Edla's hospitality and kindness transformed the peddler completely. He decided to mend his wrong ways and return the thirty kronors that he had stolen. So he wrapped the notes and a rattrap in a package and left them with a note addressed to Edla."
    },
    {
        "question": " How was Gandhi able to influence lawyers ? Give two examples ?  ",
        "answer": "Gandhi was able to influence the lawyers through his conviction earnestness and pertinent questioning. Gandhi reproached the lawyers of Muzzafarpur for charging a large sum of money as fee from the peasants. Later the lawyers from Bihar opined that they would return to their own places in the event of his imprisonment."
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the poet want for the children of the slums ? Why? ",
        "answer": "He wants the children of the slums to venture into the outside world, beyond the boundaries of their slums, and experience a better present and future life. <br> The elementary school in the slum does not serve any purpose with its poor infrastructure and disinterested students.27"
    },
    {
        "question": " In the poem ' Keeping Quiet ' does the poet advocate total inactivity and death ",
        "answer": "No, the poet does not advocate total inactivity and death. In fact, he says “What I want should not be confused with total inactivity”. He describes people walking peacefully, doing nothing. He wants us to introspect, which can happen only when one is alive and conscious."
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you infer from Sam's letter to charley? ",
        "answer": "The letter was addressed to Charley. In the letter Sam had informed Charley that he was living on the third level. He had also told Charley and his wife to keep looking for the third level. Clearly the letter was a product of Charley's imagination."
    },
    {
        "question": "why is an adult's perspective on life different from that of child's ? ",
        "answer": ": An adult's perspective on life is different from that of a child because of the difference between their respective experiences and exposure to the world around them. An adult comes across all sorts of experiences—good or bad, pleasant or unpleasant, happy or sad, encouraging or discouraging."
    },
    {
        "question": " Why do celebrities find fault with an interview ? ",
        "answer": "Most of the celebrities find faults with being interviewed because they feel it is an 'unnecessary invasion' into their personal lives. They believe it tarnishes their image and victimizes them."
    },
    {
        "question": "The reader's sympathy is with the peddler right from the beginning of the story . Why is this so ? Is the sympathy justified? ",
        "answer": "The sympathy is justified because in the end we find out that the peddler is capable of appreciating genuine goodness and hospitality. When he is treated with respect and kindness, he reciprocates the same in the best way he can."
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is Antarctica the place to go to the understand the past , present and future of the planet earth  ? ",
        "answer": "The ice-sheets are breaking, and thus, global warming is setting in. Also, the beauty of the existing ice covered oceans is a source of inspiration to do whatever is possible to save and preserve its natural resources. Thus, Antarctica is definitely the place to go to understand the world."
    },
    {
        "question": " What happened at the Golden Lion Hotel ? (Evans tries an O-level)",
        "answer": "He left fake clues to misguide the officials chasing him. Even as the Governor heaved a sigh of relief after nabbing him in the Golden Lion hotel, Evans was secretly cooking and executing another path of escape. The prison officer and the van used by the Governor for transferring Evans back to the prison were forged."
    },
]








let dataHtml = document.getElementById('dataEntry')

// showData(Flamingo)




function showData(whichBook) {

    for (let i = 0; i < whichBook.length; i++) {
        let wordsLength = whichBook[i].answer.split(" ").length
        console.log(wordsLength)
        dataHtml.innerHTML += `
    <p class="btn btn-success  w-100" >
     ${whichBook[i].question}
     <p>Answer Length : ${wordsLength} words</p>
    </p>
  
  
    <div class="card card-body">
    ${whichBook[i].answer}
      
    </div>

<br>

<br>`

    }
document.getElementById("tQue").innerText = whichBook.length + " Important Questions"

}


function clickedShow(a) {
    dataHtml.innerHTML = ""
    showData(a)
}

showData(Flamingo)
